Aliaksei Saroka Minsk, Belarus +375336389581 lehaSVV2009@gmail.com

Summary

5 years experience Full Stack Developer. Having fun with programming (backend or frontend, office or remote, paid or open source) and traveling. Trying to be useful in any team. Currently welcome to relocation offered jobs.

Skills

Java: 5 yearsJavaScript: 5 yearsSpring: 4 yearsReact JS: 3 years

Experience

Full Stack Developer, -, 12/2018 - 2/2019

Simple battleship-like board game. Personally I designed and implemented entire game which includes game logic, frontend, backend for online game and AI bot.

- React
- Material UI
- Styled Components
- boardgame.io
- three.js
- brain.js

Full Stack Developer, Issoft Solutions, 5/2018 - 11/2018

React Question Board for meetings and planning using Interaxo document management system. Within the project I designed and implemented robust and secure REST API for the app and implemented new web pages like filterable cards list page, card forms, auth page, etc. Additionally I introduced a new library for all common components that are used across React applications of the customer. Plus configured CI, deployment and analytics. Now the project is easily scaled, monitored and successfully used by different customers who wants more and more new features.

- Spring
- REST API
- Hibernate
- PostgreSQL
- React
- Material UI
- Redux
- React DnD
- React Virtualized

Frontend Lead Developer, -, 6/2018 - 9/2018

Web project with courses for students and teachers. I implemented some new views and integrated the project with existing API according to the client requirements. I also introduced the project to new developers, tried to teach them project best practices, helped them and monitored their work.

- React
- Redux
- Styled Components
- React Player
- Swagger

Backend Developer, Issoft Solutions, 2/2018 - 5/2018

Application allows to set up external workflow for different folders in document management system. Within the project with help of mentor I implemented the application that synchronizes folders in workflow using document management system API. Now the application is successfully used by several document management clients to simplify their real workflow.

- Spring
- REST API
- Hibernate
- Apache Camel
- WebSocket

Frontend Developer, -, 3/2018 - 4/2018

Pinterest like room fittings. I set up frontend app, implemented registration and authentication flow, build responsive pinterest view and set up bitbucket pipelines. Now the client rapidly reviews the changes of client developers, offers new users a personal account, monitors new users and enjoys pinterest view for the products.

- React
- Material UI
- Redux
- React Stack Grid

Frontend Developer, -, 11/2017 - 2/2018

Real estate search app. I used Material-UI Grid layout system to make application responsive, Material UI to create nice views, migrated sass to css-in-js to clean up sass files, replaced webpack config with create-react-app scripts and refactored plenty of code. Now the project is completely responsive and easier to read, support and implement new features.

- React
- Material UI
- Redux
- Leaflet

Backend Developer, Issoft Solutions, 1/2017 - 1/2018

REST Public API for big document management system. I spent a lot of time learning REST API best practices and with help of mentor I implemented Public API, which is monitored, covered by different types of tests, secured by OAuth2, well-documented, versionable and follow many REST API best practices. Now API is successfully used by many internal document management system applications as well as external document management customer applications.

Spring

- REST API
- OpenID Connect
- OAuth2
- Keycloak
- Retrofit
- Swagger
- Docker
- Openshift

Backend Developer, Issoft Solutions, 7/2017 - 8/2017

Web and mobile applications for medical items monitoring on ships. I fixed all the bugs, provided by the client, and some bugs found by me in Spring Data logic and deployment to AWS. Now the application is used by captains and crew members on ships.

- Spring
- Hibernate
- Spock
- AWS EC2
- Bamboo

Full Stack Developer, Issoft Solutions, 10/2014 - 1/2017

Enterprise document management system for engineering and oil industry in Norway. By the end date I've learnt all the areas of the application and have been able to quickly find and fix any bugs. I improved some areas like bulk import, download, upload, email handling, security, mobile app, etc. I also refactored a lot of code. Now the amount of the application users and new features still rapidly grows while the amount of bugs grows not so fast as it was before areas improvements.

- Spring
- Alfresco
- CMIS
- JUnit
- Gradle
- ExtJS
- Cordova/Phonegap
- Google Analytics
- Jenkins
- Git

Java Developer, IBA Group, 8/2014 - 10/2014

Support of bank content management system.

IBM Tivoli Storage Manager

Full Stack Developer, IBA Group, 2/2014 - 8/2014

Web based bank document management system.

- Apache Struts
- Dojo
- Ant
- IBM FileNet
- IBM WebSphere
- Apache POI

• SVN

Java Developer, IBA Group, 9/2013 - 2/2014

Web based document management system.

- JSP
- Servlets
- XSLT
- Maven
- IBM FileNet
- IBM WebSphere
- Apache POI
- SVN

Education

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, 6/2016 Artificial intelligence

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, 6/2018 Ergonomics

Publications

• Al Knowledge base in cookery, BSUIR

Profiles

- Github, lehaSVV2009
- LinkedIn, <u>aliaksei-saroka</u>
- Skype, <u>csi.alexsoroka</u>
- Instagram, specialforkadet